Guide to the Institute of Pacific Relations Records
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Part II. American Institute of Pacific Relations, 1926-1959 and Miscellaneous Committee Files
  - American Institute of Pacific Relations, 1926-1959 and Miscellaneous Committee Files
    - 1943 (Box 179-180)
      - Shahn, Tillie (Box 187)
      - Southern California Office (Box 187)
      - Sproul, Robert G. (Box 187)
      - Student Conference
        - General (Box 187)
        - Correspondence (Box 187)
      - T (Box 188)
      - Tarr, Edgar J. (Box 188)
      - Test Project (Box 188)
      - Time, Incorporated (Box 188)
      - Timetables (Box 188)
      - U (Box 188)
      - United China Relief
        - General (Box 188)
        - Appropriation Committee (Box 188)
        - Executive Committee (Box 188)
        - Program Committee (Box 188)
      - V (Box 188)
      - W (Box 188)
      - Walsh, Richard J. (Box 188)
      - Washington Study Group (Box 188)
      - Wilbur, Ray Lyman (Box 188)
      - Y (Box 188)
      - Z (Box 188)
    - 1944
      - A (Box 189)
      - American Council, IPR
        - General (Box 189)
        - Auditor's Report (Box 189)
        - Board of Trustees (Box 189)
        - Executive Committee
          - Correspondence (Box 189)
          - Meetings and Reports (Box 189)
        - Library (Box 189)
        - Membership (Box 189)
        - Pacific Council (Box 189)
        - Pamphlets (Box 189)
        - Nominating Committee (Box 189)
        - Personnel (Job Analysis) (Box 189)
        - Research Committee (Box 189)
        - Research Program (Box 189)
        - Staff Meetings (Box 189)
      - American Policy and the Chinese Revolution (Box 189)
      - Applicants (Box 189)
      - Australian American Cooperation (Box 189)
      - B (Box 189)
      - Berendsen, Carl August (Box 189)
      - C (Box 190)
      - Chicago Office (Box 190)
      - China Conference (Box 190)
      - China - America Council of Commerce and Industry (Box 190)
      - China's Crisis (Box 190)
      - Chinese
        - American Discussion (Box 190)
        - American Study Group, New York (Box 190)
        - American Study Group, Washington (Box 190)
      - CIO Memoranda by IPR (Box 190)
      - D (Box 191)
      - Dennett, Raymond
        - Trip, 1944 May (Box 191)
        - Trip to Chicago, 1944 May (Box 191)
        - Trip to Cleveland, 1944 May (Box 191)
        - Trip to Denver, 1944 May (Box 191)
        - Trip to Los Angeles, 1944 May (Box 191)
        - Trip to Milwaukee, 1944 May (Box 191)
        - Trip to San Francisco, 1944 May (Box 191)
        - Trip to Seattle, 1944 May (Box 191)
        - Trip to West Coast, 1944 May (Box 191)
        - Miscellaneous for Trips, 1944 May (Box 191)
      - Dennett, Tyler (Box 191)
      - Division of Cultural Relations (Box 191)
      - Downtown Luncheons (Box 191)
      - E (Box 191)
      - Eggleston Luncheon (Box 191)
      - Emerson, Rupert (Box 191)
      - F (Box 192)
      - Far Eastern Survey (Box 192)
      - Foreign Policy Association (Box 192)
      - G (Box 192)
      - H (Box 192)
      - Hawaii Office (Box 192)
      - Holland, W.L. (Box 192)
      - I (Box 192)
      - India Study (Box 192)
      - International Research Fund (Box 192)
      - J (Box 192)
      - Japan (Box 192)
      - Japanese Americans in Peace and War (Box 192)
      - Japanese in Hawaii (Box 192)
      - Jayson, Alice (Box 192)
      - Johnstone, William C. (Box 192)
      - K (Box 193)
      - Kohlberg, Alfred (Box 193)
      - L (Box 193)
      - Labor in China (Box 193)
      - Lasker, Bruno (Box 193)
      - Lattimore, Eleanor (Box 193)
      - Lattimore Luncheon, 1944 July 7 (Box 193)
      - M (Box 193)
      - Mc (Box 193)
      - McConaughy, James L. (Box 193)
      - Milwaukee Office (Box 193)
      - Moscow-Pullman (Box 193)
      - N (Box 193)
      - O (Box 193)
      - Pacific Council, IPR
        - Interim Meetings (Box 193)
        - Notices to National Councils (Box 193)
      - Pacific Northwest Office (Box 193)
      - Policy of Secretary of State Stimson Toward China (Box 193)
      - Porter, Catherine (Box 193)
      - Purcell Dinner, 1944 October 19 (Box 193)
      - R (Box 194)
      - Regional Offices (Box 194)
      - Rockefeller Foundation (Box 194)
      - Royal Institute of International Affairs (Box 194)
      - S (Box 194)
      - Salisbury, Laurence (Box 194)
      - San Francisco Office (Box 194)
      - Stewart, Peggy (Box 194)
      - Time, Incorporated (Box 194)
      - U (Box 194)
      - United States Shipping in Transpacific Trade (Box 194)
      - W (Box 194)
      - Washington Office (Box 194)
      - Webster Publishing Company (Box 194)
      - World Peace Foundation (Box 194)
      - X-Y-Z (Box 195)
      - Miscellaneous (12 Folders) (Box 195)
    - 1945
      - A (Box 196)
      - American Association for the United Nations, Inc. (Box 196)
      - American Council, IPR
        - General (Box 196)
        - Annual Report List (Box 196)
        - Annual Report, 1945 (related Materials) (Box 196)
        - Board of Trustees (Box 196)
        - Library (Box 196)
        - Membership (Box 196)
        - Pacific Council (Box 196)
        - Personnel (Job Analysis) (Box 196)
        - Research Committee (Box 196)
        - Research Program (Box 196)
        - Staff Meetings (Box 196)
      - American Institute of Ethnic Relations (Box 196)
      - Applicants (Box 196)
      - Arneman, G.E. (Box 196)
      - Asia on the Move (Box 196)
      - Auditor's Report (Box 196)
      - Australian-American Cooperative Movement (Box 196)
      - B (Box 196)
      - Belshaw, Horace (Box 196)
      - Bodman, Edward (Box 196)
      - Bombay Plan (Box 196)
      - Boyer Luncheon (Box 196)
      - C (Box 196)
      - Canadian Institute of International Affairs (Box 196)
      - Carnegie Corporation (Box 196)
      - Carter, Edward C.
        - American Council (Box 196)
        - Luncheon, 1945 November 7 (Box 196)
      - Chatham House Correspondence (Box 196)
      - Chicago Office (Box 196)
      - China-America Council of Commerce and Industry (Box 196)
      - D (Box 197)
      - Dennett, Raymond (Box 197)
      - Dennett, Tyler (Box 197)
      - Downtown Luncheons (Box 197)
      - E (Box 197)
      - Ewing, Ethel (Box 197)
      - F (Box 197)
      - Far Eastern Survey (Box 197)
      - Field, Frederick V. (Box 197)
      - Financial Campaign
        - Appointments (Box 197)
        - Corporation Lists (Box 197)
        - Executive Committee Expenses (Box 197)
      - Future of Japan (Box 197)
      - G (Box 197)
      - Gammans Luncheon, 1945 January 30 (Box 197)
      - Governing of Men (Box 197)
      - H (Box 197)
      - Hawaii Office (Box 197)
      - Helmick, Milton J. (Box 197)
      - Heymann, Hans (Box 197)
      - I (Box 197)
      - India Study (Box 197)
      - Institute of Pacific Relations Conference on Japanese Character Structure (Box 197)
      - International Secretariat Report (Box 197)
      - J (Box 197)
      - Jenkins, Shirley (Box 197)
      - Johnston, Eric (Box 197)
      - Johnstone, William C. (Box 197)
      - K (Box 198)
      - Kohlberg, Alfred (Box 198)
      - Kalaw Luncheon, 1945 October 23 (Box 198)
      - Kunzru, H.N. (Box 198)
      - L (Box 198)
      - Lasker, Bruno (Box 198)
      - Lee, Rosamond (Box 198)
      - M (Box 198)
      - Mc (Box 198)
      - Mansfield, Mike (Box 198)
      - Mass Education in China (Box 198)
      - Milwaukee Office (Box 198)
      - Moscow-Pullman (Box 198)
      - N (Box 198)
      - National Councils (Box 198)
      - O (Box 198)
      - P (Box 198)
      - Pacific Council
        - General (Box 198)
        - Reports (Box 198)
      - Princeton University Press (Box 198)
      - Program Committee (Box 198)
      - R (Box 198)
      - Rao Luncheon (Box 198)
      - Regional Offices (Box 198)
      - Royal Institute of International Affairs (Box 198)
      - S (Box 199)
      - Salisbury, Laurence (Box 199)
      - San Francisco Office
        - General (Box 199)
        - UNCIO Committee (Box 199)
      - Schatz, Louise (Box 199)
      - Seattle Office (Box 199)
      - Security in the Pacific (Box 199)
      - Shahn, Tillie (Box 199)
      - Speakers Bureau (Box 199)
      - T (Box 199)
      - U (Box 199)
      - V (Box 199)
      - W (Box 199)
      - War and Peace Fund (Box 199)
      - Washington Lunch (Box 199)
      - World Peace Foundation (Box 199)
      - Y (Box 199)
    - 1946
      - A (Box 200)
      - Adloff, Richard (Box 200)
      - Adloff, Richard and Virginia (Box 200)
      - American Association for the United Nations (Box 200)
      - American Council, IPR
        - Annual Report (Box 200)
        - Annual Report List (Box 200)
        - Board of Trustees Comments on Annual Report (Box 200)
        - Correspondence of Members (Box 200)
        - Education Advisory Committee (Box 200)
        - Executive Committee Correspondence (Box 200)
        - General Correspondence (Box 201)
        - London (Box 201)
        - Nominating Committee (Box 201)
        - Pamphlets (Box 201)
        - Research Committee Correspondence (Box 201)
        - Research Program (Box 201)
        - Staff Meetings and Memoranda (Box 201)
      - American People's Fund (Box 201)
      - Auditor's Report (Box 201)
      - Australian-American Cooperation Movement (Box 201)
      - Australian Institute of International Affairs (Box 201)
      - B (Box 201)
      - Board of Trustees Membership List (Box 201)
      - Board of Trustees Nominations (Box 201)
      - By-Laws Subcommittee (2 Folders) (Box 201)
      - C (Box 202)
      - Canadian Institute of International Affairs (Box 202)
      - Carnegie Corporation (Box 202)
      - Carter, Edward C. (Box 202)
      - Conant, Melvin (Box 202)
      - Conference of National Organizations for the United Nations (Box 202)
      - Conference on China and the Far East (Box 202)
      - D (Box 202)
      - Downtown Luncheons (Box 202)
      - E (Box 203)
      - Emeny, Brooks
        - Cleveland Council on World Affairs (Box 203)
        - Proposed Conference (Box 203)
      - F (Box 203)
      - Far Eastern Survey
        - General (Box 203)
        - Releases (Box 203)
      - Farley, Miriam S. (Box 203)
      - Field, Frederick V. (Box 203)
      - Films (Box 203)
      - Finances (Box 203)
      - Financial Campaign (Box 203)
      - Foreign Policy Association (Box 203)
      - G (Box 203)
      - Guthman, Renée (Box 203)
      - H (Box 204)
      - Hawaii Office (Box 204)
      - Healy, Mary (Box 204)
      - Hoffman, Paul G. (Box 204)
      - Holcombe, Chester (Box 204)
      - Holland, W.L. (Box 204)
      - I (Box 204)
      - IPR Publications
        (IPR Bulletin transferred to IPR History)
      - Inland-Empire Division (Box 204)
      - In-service Course (Box 204)
      - International Finance - American, Pacific Councils (Box 204)
      - International Organization Meeting (Box 204)
      - International Research (Box 204)
      - International Secretariat (Box 204)
      - J (Box 205)
      - Japan--General (Box 205)
      - Japanese-American Committee for Democracy (Box 205)
      - Jenkins, Shirley (Box 205)
      - Johnstone, William C. (Box 205)
      - K (Box 205)
      - Kohlberg, Alfred (Box 205)
      - L (Box 205)
      - Lao Sheh (Box 205)
      - Lapham, Lewis (Box 205)
      - Lasker, Bruno (Box 205)
      - Lew, Daniel (Box 205)
      - Library (Box 205)
      - Lilienthal, Philip K. (Box 205)
      - Lindsay, Michael
        - General (Box 205)
        - Military Prospects in a Chinese Civil War (Box 205)
      - Los Angeles Division (Box 205)
      - Lower, ARM (Box 205)
      - M (Box 205)
      - Mac (Box 205)
      - Memos: Office Procedure for Meetings (Box 206)
      - Milwaukee Office (Box 206)
      - Morris, Wilson (Box 206)
      - Mott, Celestine (Box 206)
      - Myers, Fred (Box 206)
      - N (Box 206)
      - National Councils 19*+6 (Box 206)
      - Nominating Committee 6 Nov 19^+6 (Box 206)
      - O (Box 206)
      - P (Box 206)
      - Pacific Council (Box 206)
      - Pacific Science Conference (Box 206)
      - Princeton University Press (Box 206)
      - Progress Reports (Box 206)
      - Publications Catalogue (Box 206)
      - R (Box 206)
      - Regional Membership Information (Box 206)
      - Regional Offices (Box 206)
      - Research Projects Under Way, 1946 July 9 (Box 206)
      - Ribeiro, Lyra (Box 207)
      - Rockefeller Foundation (Box 207)
      - Royal Institute of International Affairs (Box 207)
      - S (Box 207)
      - Salisbury, Laurence (Box 207)
      - San Francisco Office
        - General (Box 207)
        - McLaughlin, Emma (Box 207)
        - Rauch, Laura (Box 207)
        - White, Lynn (Box 207)
      - Schatz, Louise (Box 207)
      - Schreiber, Julius--Discussion Guide Pamphlet (Box 207)
      - Seattle Office
        - General (Box 207)
        - Little, Herbert S. (Box 207)
        - Martin, Charles E. (Box 208)
      - Security in the Pacific (Box 208)
      - Shahn, Tillie (Box 208)
      - Sharpe, Frances (Box 208)
      - Southeast Asia Institute (Box 208)
      - Sproul, Robert G. (Box 208)
      - Staley, Eugene
        - General (Box 208)
        - Memo on Chinese Industrialization Studies (Box 208)
      - Stewart, Marguerite Ann (Box 208)
      - T (Box 208)
      - Taylor, George E. (Box 208)
      - Treatment of Asia in American Textbooks (Box 208)
      - U (Box 209)
      - Uchida, Y (Box 209)
      - Ussachevsky, Betty (Box 209)
      - V (Box 209)
      - W (Box 209)
      - Washington Office, IPR
        - Coville, Lillian (Box 209)
        - Pollard, John A. (Box 209)
      - Weingard, David (Box 209)
      - Whitney Foundation (Box 209)
      - Wilbur, C. Martin (Box 209)
      - Williams, Pierce (Box 209)
      - Y (Box 209)
      - Z (Box 209)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 210-214)
    - 1947
      - A (Box 215)
      - American Council, IPR
        - Budget Subcommittee (Box 215)
        - Education Advisory Committee (Box 215)
        - Executive Committee Correspondence (Box 215)
        - Wominationg Committee (Box 215)
        - Research: Other Organizations (Box 215)
        - Research Committee Correspondence (Box 215)
      - American People's Fund (Box 215)
      - American Russian Institute (Box 215)
      - Asia Conference (Box 215)
      - Auditor’ s Report (Box 215)
      - B (Box 215)
      - Biggerstaff, Knight (Box 216)
      - Board of Trustees (Box 216)
      - Borg, Dorothy (Box 216)
      - C (Box 217)
      - Carnegie Corporation (Box 217)
      - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace (Box 217)
      - Carter, Edward C. (Box 217)
      - Conant, Melvin (Box 217)
      - Corbett, Percy E. (Box 217)
      - Council on Foreign Relations (Box 217)
      - Council on World Affairs (Box 217)
      - Crossman, Edgar G. (Box 217)
      - D (Box 218)
      - Davidson, C. Girard (Box 218)
      - Dean, Arthur H. (Box 218)
      - Downtown Luncheons
        - General (Box 218)
        - Crossman, Edgar G. (Box 218)
        - Heyworth, J. Lawrence (Box 218)
        - Holland, W.L. (Box 218)
        - Jacoby-White (Box 218)
        - Japan (Box 218)
        - Lattimore, Owen (Box 218)
        - Peffer, Nathaniel (Box 218)
        - Rockefeller, John D., III (Box 218)
        - Ward, Barbara (Box 218)
      - E (Box 218)
      - F (Box 218)
      - Far Eastern Survey (Box 218)
      - Farley, Miriam S. (Box 218)
      - Field, Frederick V. (Box 218)
      - Films (Box 218)
      - Finance (Box 218)
      - Gilchrist, Huntington (Box 219)
      - Grant Foundation (Box 219)
      - H (Box 219)
      - Hawaii Office, IPR
        - General (Box 219)
        - Altree, Wayne (Box 219)
        - Loomis, Charles F. (Box 219)
      - Hazelton, Mary (Box 219)
      - Hoffman, Paul G. (Box 219)
      - Holland, William L. (Box 219)
      - I (Box 220)
        (See Also: Boxes 246-248)
      - International Secretariat
        - General (Box 220)
        - Far East in the News (Box 220)
        - Lilienthal, Philip (Box 220)
        - National Councils
          - Australian Institute of International Affairs (Box 220)
          - Canadian Institute of International Affairs (Box 220)
          - Royal Institute of International Affairs (Box 220)
          - 1947 (Box 220)
        - Pacific Council (Box 220)
      - IPR Bulletin
      - J (Box 221)
      - Jenkins, Shirley (Box 221)
      - Jessup, Philip C. (Box 221)
      - K (Box 221)
      - Kizer, Benjamin (Box 221)
      - Kohlberg, Alfred--Special Meeting of AIPR (Box 221)
      - L (Box 221)
      - Lasker, Bruno (Box 221)
      - Lattimore, Eleanor (Box 221)
      - Lattimore, Owen
        - General (Box 221)
        - Meeting, 1947 December 9 (Box 221)
      - Lewis, Aleksandra--Incident (Box 221)
      - Letters--Carter, Edward C. (Box 222)
      - Library (Box 222)
      - Lockwood, W.V. (Box 222)
      - Los Angeles (Box 222)
      - M (Box 222)
      - Mailings (Box 222)
      - Mc (Box 222)
      - Membership Lists (Box 222)
      - Milwaukee (Box 222)
      - Mott, Celestine (Box 222)
      - Myers, Fred (Box 222)
      - N (Box 223)
      - O (Box 223)
      - P (Box 223)
      - Pacific Story (Box 223)
      - Plain Talk (Box 223)
      - Q (Box 223)
      - R (2 Folders) (Box 224)
      - Regional Offices (Box 224)
      - Rockefeller Foundation (Box 224)
      - Rockefeller Luncheon (Box 224)
      - S (Box 224)
      - Salisbury, Laurence (Box 224)
      - San Francisco Office, IPR
        - General (Box 224)
        - McLaughlin, Emma M (Box 224)
        - Rauch, Laura (Box 224)
        - White, Lynn (Box 224)
      - Schatz, Louise H. (Box 225)
      - Schreiber, Julius--Zero Hour in China (Box 225)
      - Seattle Office, IPR
        - General (Box 225)
        - Little, Herbert (Box 225)
        - Martin, Charles (Box 225)
        - Rockwood, Charles (Box 225)
      - Seeger, Elizabeth (Box 225)
      - Shahn, Tillie (Box 226)
      - Smothers, Frank (Box 226)
      - Southeast Asia Institute (Box 226)
      - Sproul, Robert G. (Box 226)
      - Staff (Box 226)
      - Staley, Eugene (Box 226)
      - Stewart, Marguerite Ann (Box 226)
      - Stock Room (Box 226)
      - Straus, Donald B. (Box 226)
      - T (Box 226)
      - Taylor, George E. (Box 226)
      - Treasury Department Report (Box 226)
      - U (Box 226)
      - Uchida, Yoshi (Box 226)
      - Union--Shop Committee (Box 226)
      - V (Box 227)
      - W (Box 227)
      - Ward, Barbara
        - General (Box 227)
        - Dinner, 1947 May 5 (Box 227)
      - Miscellaneous (7 Folders) (Box 228)
    - 1948
      - A (Box 229)
      - American Association for the United Nations (Box 229)
      - American Council, IPR
        - Auditor's Report (Box 229)
        - Budget (Box 229)
        - Compliments (Box 229)
        - Executive Committee Correspondence (Box 229)
        - Nominating Committee (Box 229)
      - American Russian Institute (Box 229)
      - Applicants (Box 229)
      - Board of Trustees (Box 230)
      - Boardman, Eugene P.--Far Eastern Institute (Box 230)
      - Bodde, Derk--Poll on Aid to China (Box 230)
      - Borg, Dorothy (Box 230)
      - Brodhead, Charles D.--Modern Asiatic History Outline (Box 230)
      - Bulletin-IPR (Box 230)
      - C (Box 230)
      - Carnegie Corporation (Box 231)
      - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace (Box 231)
      - Carter, Edward C.
        - General (Box 231)
        - Luncheon, 1948 November 29 (Box 231)
      - China Pamphlet (Box 231)
      - Conant, Melvin A. (Box 231)
      - Council on Foreign Relations (Box 231)
      - Council on World Affairs (Box 231)
      - Crank file (Box 231)
      - D (Box 232)
      - Dean, Arthur H. (Box 232)
      - Downtown and Uptown Luncheons (Box 232)
      - E (Box 232)
      - Emeny, Brooks (Box 232)
      - F (Box 232)
      - Fairbank, John K. (Box 232)
      - Far Eastern Survey (Box 232)
      - Finance (Box 232)
      - Foreign Policy Association (Box 232)
      - G (Box 233)
      - Greene, Katrine R.C. (Box 233)
      - H (Box 233)
      - Hawaii Office, IPR
        - General (Box 233)
        - Loomis, Charles F. (Box 233)
      - Holland, William L. (Box 233)
      - I (Box 234)
      - Inland Office Group (Box 234)
      - International Secretariat
        - General (Box 234)
        - National Councils (Box 234)
        - Other National Councils (Box 234)
        - Pacific Council (Box 234)
      - Inter-office Correspondence (Box 234)
      - Inter-organization
        - General (Box 234)
        - Films (Box 234)
        - Mass Organization (Box 234)
        - Research Funds (Box 234)
        - Student ships (Box 234)
        - United Nations Documents (Box 234)
      - J (Box 235)
      - James, Roy E. (Box 235)
      - Jenkins, Shirley (Box 235)
      - Jessup, Philip C. (Box 235)
      - K (Box 235)
      - Kizer, Benjamin H. (Box 235)
      - Kohlberg, Alfred Inc.--Chinese Textiles (Box 235)
      - L (Box 235)
      - Lane, Clayton
        - General (Box 235)
        - Speech Material (Box 235)
        - Washington, 1948 November (Box 235)
      - Lasker, Bruno (Box 235)
      - Lattimore, Eleanor (Box 235)
      - Lattimore, Owen (Box 235)
      - Lilienthal, Philip (Box 235)
      - Lockwood, W.W. (Box 235)
      - Los Angeles Office, I.P.R. (Box 235)
      - M (Box 236)
      - Membership
        - Dues and Privileges (Box 236)
        - Letter (Box 236)
        - Lists (Box 236)
        - Prospects (Box 236)
        - Statistics (Box 236)
      - Mott, Celestine. T
        - General (Box 236)
        - Report (Box 236)
      - N (Box 236)
      - National Foreign Trade Council (Box 236)
      - News of the IPR (Box 236)
      - O (Box 237)
      - Organic Union (Box 237)
      - P (Box 237)
      - Pope, Arthur Upham (Box 237)
      - Publications, IPR (Box 237)
      - R (Box 237)
      - Regional Offices (Box 237)
      - Research Reports (Box 237)
      - Rockefeller Foundation (Box 237)
      - S (Box 238)
      - Salisbury, Laurence E. (Box 238)
      - San Francisco Office, IPR--Staley, Eugene (Box 238)
      - San Francisco World Affairs Council (2 Folders) (Box 238)
      - Seattle Office, I.P.R.
        - General (Box 238)
        - Little, Herbert S. (Box 238)
        - Martin, Charles (Box 238)
        - Rockwood, Charles (Box 239)
      - Shahn, Tillie G. (Box 239)
      - Sproul, Robert G. (Box 239)
      - Straus, Donald B. (Box 239)
      - Successor Committee (Box 239)
      - Syracuse University Conference (Box 239)
      - T (Box 240)
      - Talbot, Phillips (Box 240)
      - Taylor, George E. (Box 240)
      - Tewksbury, Donald G. (Box 240)
      - U (Box 240)
      - UNESCO Conference--Pacific Coast (Box 240)
      - Union--Shop Committee (Box 240)
      - V (Box 240)
      - W (Box 240)
      - Washington Group (Box 240)
      - Washington, D.C. Office, IPR--Guthman, Renee (Box 240)
      - Webster Publishing Company (Box 240)
      - Wilbur, Ray Lyman (Box 240)
      - X-Y-Z (Box 241)
      - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1948 February-December (10 Folders) (Box 241)
    - 1949
      - A (Box 242)
      - American Association for the UN (Box 242)
      - American IPR
        - Auditors Report (Box 242)
        - Board of Trustees (Box 242)
        - Budget (Box 242)
        - Executive Committee (Box 242)
        - Nominating Committee (Box 242)
        - Research Committee (Box 242)
      - American Russian Institute (Box 242)
      - Annual Meeting (Box 242)
      - Applicants (Box 242)
      - B (2 Folders) (Box 243)
      - Borg, Dorothy (Box 243)
      - Brownell, Lincoln C. (Box 243)
      - C (2 Folders) (Box 243)
      - Carnegie Corporation (Box 243)
      - Carnegie Endowment (Box 243)
      - Carnegie Endowment
        - Denver Conference (Box 243)
        - Notes & Forecasts (Box 243)
      - Carter, Edward C. (Box 243)